folkd.com 2009-06-08

# folkd.com - Enrich your websurfing experience

Folkd respects and protects the privacy of the individuals that use folkd services ("website and software"). Individually identifiable information about you is not willfully disclosed to anyone without first receiving your permission, as explained in this privacy policy.

**1\. Cookies**  
Upon your first use of folkd services, folkd.com sends a "cookie" to your computer. A cookie is a piece of data that identifies you as a unique user. folkd uses cookies to store your preferences such as your screen name. Folkd.com will not disclose its cookies to third parties except as required by a valid legal process such as a search warrant, subpoena, statute, or court order.

Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. Be aware, however, that the folkd services may not function properly if you refuse cookies.

**2\. Collection of user data**

Folkd does not collect any unique information about you (such as your name, adress, etc.) except when you specifically and knowingly provide such information, as in our registration process. This unique information is associated with a user identifier for the purpose of improving your web-surfing experience. Information you provide, with the exception of your email address, will also be displayed on your profile page which is viewable by other users of folkd services. Note that providing personal information is not necessary to use folkd services.

Folkd also notes and saves information such as time of day, browser type, browser language, and IP address with each visit to the folkd.com website. This information is collected automatically by almost all major web servers. Folkd uses this information only in aggregate or anonymous form to determine the composition of our userbase, and the load on our servers, so that we can serve you better.

Periodically, the folkd software contacts our servers to see if you are running the most current version. If necessary, we will automatically provide you with the latest update.

**3\. Receive and display related content**

In order to receive and display related content to the webpage you are actually surfing, folkd software ("browser extension") provides the browsers URL and page-title to the folkd server with every navigation event, but:  
\- Folkd does **NOT** collect these user-related "history data" - meaning which user has surfed which pages.  
\- Folkd does **NOT** process any data from security related pages "https://" (e.g. online banking) or pages located outside of public domains "http://" (e.g. you local file system file://).

The "related contents" are entirely out of our control. As such, folkd.com takes no responsibility for them. If you are using the contents provided by the folkd browser extension and thereby arrive at other websites, note that these sites are NOT related to folkd.com and may send their own cookies to users, collect data, or solicit personal information.

**4\. Submit information to folkd**

When you click on the buttons in the folkd browser extension, you are explicitly sending information and/or data about your preferences for the site currently displayed in your browser. Folkd uses these data to improve its service and provide more related information to other users of folkd services. By default, information you provide is marked as "public". If you don`t want to share a certain information, mark it as "private". Please be aware that due to possible errors within the system there is the risk of your data being accessed by other users of folkd service - so we advise you to not provide security relevant information (e.g. passwords), even if marked as "private".  
URL`s which are processed within public domain, but proteced by password, will automatically be marked as private

**5\. Sharing personal information**

We do not share any personally identifiable information that is not already available on your profile page with anyone without your express written consent. However, we may share some aggregate or anonymous information about our userbase with sponsors and business partners. For example, we may disclose how frequently the average folkd user uses certain services, or how many users are signed up for a given interest. Please be aware, however, that we will release specific personal information about you if required to do so in order to comply with any valid legal process such as a search warrant, subpoena, statute, or court order.

Notice that providing personal information (exept your username and email adress) is not necessary to use folkd services. 

**6\. Information policy / Newsletter**

As a user of folkd services you agree to receive communications from folkd.com to the provided email adress or your inbox. These Emails are to inform you about folkd contents or updates of folkd service or e.g. to recover lost passwords. If you don't want to receive our information you can easily opt-out through your users profile settings.

In addition our services give you the opportunity to opt-in to watch certain tags or users contents. If you choose to receive them, these messages will be sent periodically.

**7\. Changes to the Privacy Policy**

By using the folkd services, you consent to the collection and use of your information as we have outlined in this policy and to our Terms of Use. Folkd.com may decide to change this Privacy Policy from time to time. When we do, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of the information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.

**Contact the administration team**

If you have any further questions regarding privacy or the folkd services in general, feel free to contact our administration team:

feedback (AT) folkd DOT com

Effective Date: Mai 24, 2006
